<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Evolution Of A Studio]]></title><description><![CDATA[Welcome to 600sqft of family life in NYC]]></description><link>https://evolutionofastudio.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 03:53:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[How we use mirrors to fake a view]]></title><description><![CDATA[Before we bought this place, one of the drawbacks (for me) was that the apartment only had one row of windows on ONE wall. It wasn’t a deal…]]></description><link>https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/how-we-use-mirrors-to-fake-a-view/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/how-we-use-mirrors-to-fake-a-view/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Before we bought this place, one of the drawbacks (for me) was that the apartment only had one row of windows on ONE wall. It wasn’t a deal breaker though. After all, the windows were pretty large and the space was still well lit. But I’ll be frank; I still wanted more windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s a trick we picked up from our entrepreneur friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/alexisdamen/&quot;&gt;Alexis Damen&lt;/a&gt;, creator of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/allnaturalproject/&quot;&gt;All Natural Project&lt;/a&gt; (I’m featured in one of her posts btw so check it out)! We visited their apartment in Brooklyn, and I noticed their place felt airier than the last time we were there. It turns out the only difference was a mirror hung RIGHT next to the windows on the adjacent wall. I thought it was another window! It let more light in, and added more dimension to their space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you don’t want to fake a corner window view, a mirror on the adjacent wall is a generally a good spot to reflect light back into a room. We chose a tall mirror that mimics the dimensions of one of our windows. It was very affordable (another IKEA purchase ftw) and satisfies my inner/outer desire for more windows in the studio apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FYI we have 3 more mirrors hanging strategically in our apartment. More on that in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Version 1.0]]></title><description><![CDATA[Two years ago, our apartment looked SO different. We had just moved in with furniture that was catered to our previous 1BR apartment in…]]></description><link>https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/version-1.0/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/version-1.0/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, our apartment looked SO different. We had just moved in with furniture that was catered to our previous 1BR apartment in Chelsea. On top of that, we had some hard “must-haves” for the new setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Husband’s must-have: He really wanted to be able to look out the window, but not obstruct access to the window, while also not facing a wall while working at his desk. That was a must from our previous living situation that he didn’t want to give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My must-have: I wanted to keep most, if not all, of our old furniture. I needed to make it work! But I also wanted to de-emphasize the sleeping quarters as much as possible. I didn’t want it to “feel” like a studio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both these must-haves made for a really awkward Version 1.0. We kept the king size bed (bc who doesn’t love being able to eagle spread on clean sheets), but it was unavoidably large and visible from every angle it seemed. And in lieu of the wall, our desk faced… the bed? &lt;em&gt;facepalm&lt;/em&gt; Has anyone else made some VERY questionable furniture arrangement decisions that seemed like a great idea at the time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see already from previous posts, we have made some dramatic changes to our layout. Our priorities and sensibilities have since evolved. Follow us for more transformations!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The whiteboard mock interview]]></title><description><![CDATA[We decided to give our coffee table away. It seems like a small change, but it really affects how we interact with our space. The open…]]></description><link>https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-whiteboard-mock-interview/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-whiteboard-mock-interview/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We decided to give our coffee table away. It seems like a small change, but it really affects how we interact with our space. The open carpet area now encourages us to sit and crawl with the baby, something we want to do more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, it was easy for me to part with this piece of furniture. When we moved in, a certain someone wanted a coffee table that was low enough to comfortably rest his feet on while watching television. All I cared about was a combination of aesthetics and practicality: “Just pick something that looks nice. Bonus points for some hidden storage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodbye, coffee table. For now this decision makes sense for us.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The coffee table must go]]></title><description><![CDATA[We decided to give our coffee table away. It seems like a small change, but it really affects how we interact with our space. The open…]]></description><link>https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-coffee-table-must-go/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-coffee-table-must-go/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We decided to give our coffee table away. It seems like a small change, but it really affects how we interact with our space. The open carpet area now encourages us to sit and crawl with the baby, something we want to do more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, it was easy for me to part with this piece of furniture. When we moved in, a certain someone wanted a coffee table that was low enough to comfortably rest his feet on while watching television. All I cared about was a combination of aesthetics and practicality: “Just pick something that looks nice. Bonus points for some hidden storage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodbye, coffee table. For now this decision makes sense for us.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The crappy dinner party (pre-baby)]]></title><description><![CDATA[Our first, official “Crappy Dinner Party” was a few months after moving into the studio apartment. I was inspired by an article in  The…]]></description><link>https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-crappy-dinner-party-pre-baby/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-crappy-dinner-party-pre-baby/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Our first, official “Crappy Dinner Party” was a few months after moving into the studio apartment. I was inspired by an article in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thekitchn.com/5-rules-for-hosting-a-crappy-dinner-party-235815&quot;&gt;The Kitchn&lt;/a&gt; to focus on hosting our friends, and not on  the dinner, the party, or the state of the apartment. We took this concept to heart and immediately invited our friends over. We expanded our dining table, and unfolded 4 folding chairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Folding chairs are affordable space-savers when you still want extra seating. They would’ve fit in our closet, but we tucked ours behind our rocking chair by the window because we were using them so often at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ordered in Thai food via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seamless.com&quot;&gt;Seamless&lt;/a&gt; (a popular food delivery app in NYC), and drank the leftover alcohol from our wedding. Cheers to crappy dinner parties in small spaces and to friends who love you all the more for ‘em!⠀&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The acupuncture clinic]]></title><description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago, I was diagnosed with Bell’s Palsy. I woke up with my left face partially paralyzed. I couldn’t purse my lips to spit water…]]></description><link>https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-acupuncture-clinic/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-acupuncture-clinic/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I was diagnosed with Bell’s Palsy. I woke up with my left face partially paralyzed. I couldn’t purse my lips to spit water while brushing my teeth. Water went in my left eye while showering because I couldn’t blink fully. I called my dad, a doctor of Traditional Chinese Medicine. He booked a flight and came to NY to give me acupuncture treatment. I’m pretty lucky because he’s truly one of the best at what he does. We transformed our studio apartment into a pop-up acupuncture clinic – on our dining room table! Even our dimmable pendant lamp above the dining room table served as a perfect light source for our pseudo-examination table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, my condition has improved greatly! Luckily, Bell’s Palsy can be treated fully, as long as you take quick action. Note: I also saw a general practitioner and I took corticosteroids and anti-viral medication as well, which is also vital to a full and speedy recovery.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The king-size bed share]]></title><description><![CDATA[Becoming a new mom meant I wanted to experience all the things I associated with motherhood. That meant I HAD to have a traditional crib…]]></description><link>https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-king-size-bed-share/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-king-size-bed-share/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Becoming a new mom meant I wanted to experience all the things I associated with motherhood. That meant I HAD to have a traditional crib, even though a) we don’t have much space and b) we considered the possibility of bed-sharing before the baby came along. For those of us unfamiliar with the term, bed-sharing is the practice of having your baby sleep in the same bed as you. (Note: The AAP doesn’t recommend bed-sharing. We did our own research, however, and felt confident that bed-sharing was the right decision for us.) Sure enough, our little baby rarely used the crib. Four months in, we were fully committed to bed-sharing. We were ready for a floorplan update.⠀
⠀
Because of an awkward column in the corner of our alcove, we couldn’t fit a normal king-size bed in our apartment. But we really needed a king to make bed-sharing more comfortable for us. We resorted to creating a CUSTOM king-size bed. &lt;em&gt;Cue IKEA hack&lt;/em&gt; Materials: One LACK coffee table, one LACK side table, and a mini crib mattress from Amazon. We switched our sleeping orientation, and suddenly we had MORE than enough space for the three of us. Sweet dreams from our studio to yours!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How we store a king mattress under a queen bed]]></title><description><![CDATA[When we got married, I brought my full size mattress with me. We kept it for our overnight guests, instead of getting an air mattress…]]></description><link>https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/how-we-store-a-king-mattress-under-a-queen-bed/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/how-we-store-a-king-mattress-under-a-queen-bed/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When we got married, I brought my full size mattress with me. We kept it for our overnight guests, instead of getting an air mattress, because we didn’t want to sacrifice comfort for space… until we actually needed the space. In a eureka moment, we discovered some 4” thick foam twin mattresses at my sister’s place. They were thin enough to stack, which meant they’d still fit under our bed! Now we have more storage PLUS more sleeping space for our guests!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The sisters are in town again]]></title><description><![CDATA[The sisters are in town again! That means we will be hosting 4 guests in our studio apartment, adding to our family of three, for a grand…]]></description><link>https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-sisters-are-in-town-again/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/the-sisters-are-in-town-again/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The sisters are in town again! That means we will be hosting 4 guests in our studio apartment, adding to our family of three, for a grand total of SEVEN people in 600sqft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love hosting our family, which is why we prioritize and designate storage space for extra sheets, blankets, and even a true full mattress in the apartment. But you wouldn’t even notice it because it’s all hidden!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[We bought a 600sqft studio]]></title><description><![CDATA[We bought a 600sqft studio Manhattan apartment nearly two years ago, and we’ve been iterating on the layout ever since. We’ll show you how…]]></description><link>https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/we-bought-a-600sqft-studio/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://evolutionofastudio.com//blog/we-bought-a-600sqft-studio/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We bought a 600sqft studio Manhattan apartment nearly two years ago, and we’ve been iterating on the layout ever since. We’ll show you how we transform our “small” space to grow with our family of 3.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>